Young Women's Christian Association (YWCA) Of Albany, New York Records
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Administrative Files, 1863-1996; nam_apap137-1; 5.26 cubic ft.
  - New York State Resolutions, 1917; 1925; 1957; 1976; nam_apap137-1_164 (Box 1A, Folder 12)
  - Re-incorporation Agreements, 1963-1972; nam_apap137-1_165 (Box 1A, Folder 13)
  - Tenant Agreements, 1972; nam_apap137-1_166 (Box 1A, Folder 14)
  - Warranty Deeds, 1863-1939; nam_apap137-1_167 (Box 1A, Folder 15)
  - Will and Testaments, 1960-1961; 1970; nam_apap137-1_168 (Box 1A, Folder 16)
  - YWCA Construction and Renovation, 1963; nam_apap137-1_169 (Box 1A, Folder 17)
  - Youth Bureau Agreement and Day Camp Application, 1971-1974; nam_apap137-1_170 (Box 1A, Folder 18)
  - Bonds, 1906-1913; nam_apap137-1_171 (Oversized 2, Folder 1)
  - News Page, Tax Exemptions, 1940; nam_apap137-1_172 (Oversized 2, Folder 2)
  - Payroll, 1980 December-1989; nam_apap137-1_173 (Oversized 2, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer Report, Membership Ledger, 1950; 1978; 1989; nam_apap137-1_174 (Oversized 2, Folder 4)
  - Trial Balance, 1981-1988; nam_apap137-1_175 (Oversized 2, Folder 5)
- Board and Committee Files, 1930-1995; nam_apap137-2; 2.39 cubic ft.
  This series is comprised of meeting minutes, treasury reports, and correspondence from 1930 to 1995. Minutes are from the Board of Directors, Board of Trustees, Executive Committee, and various other committees within the organization. Annual Meeting minutes are also included.
  Arranged alphabetically by subject, then chronologically.
  - Advisory Committee Meeting Minutes, 1966; nam_apap137-2_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Association Review Committee, National Review Team, 1970-1979; nam_apap137-2_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ballots, 1972; 1977; nam_apap137-2_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Budget Reports, 1989-1991; Undated; nam_apap137-2_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, By-laws, Undated; nam_apap137-2_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, Correspondence, 1951-1956; nam_apap137-2_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, Correspondence, 1968-1978; nam_apap137-2_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, Correspondence, 1984-1991; nam_apap137-2_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1935-1936; nam_apap137-2_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1937; nam_apap137-2_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1939-1941; nam_apap137-2_11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1944-1945; nam_apap137-2_12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1947-1948; nam_apap137-2_13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1949-1951; nam_apap137-2_14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1952-1953; nam_apap137-2_15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1954-1955; nam_apap137-2_16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1956-1957; nam_apap137-2_17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1958-1960; nam_apap137-2_18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1961-1963; nam_apap137-2_19 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1964-1966; nam_apap137-2_20 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1967-1969; nam_apap137-2_21 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1970-1971; nam_apap137-2_22 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1972-1973; nam_apap137-2_23 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1974-1975; nam_apap137-2_24 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1976-1977; nam_apap137-2_25 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1978-1979; nam_apap137-2_26 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1980-1981; nam_apap137-2_27 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1982-1983; nam_apap137-2_28 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1984; nam_apap137-2_29 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1985; nam_apap137-2_30 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1986; nam_apap137-2_31 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1987; nam_apap137-2_32 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1988; nam_apap137-2_33 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1989; nam_apap137-2_34 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, 1990-1991; nam_apap137-2_35 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, Meeting Minutes, Undated; nam_apap137-2_36 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, and Officer Liability Insurance, 1985-1992; nam_apap137-2_37 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, Officer Lists, 1959-1990; Undated; nam_apap137-2_38 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, Orientation, 1992; nam_apap137-2_39 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, Reports and Balance Sheets, 1953; nam_apap137-2_40 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, Responsibilities, Undated; nam_apap137-2_41 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, Statement of Assets and Liabilities, 1978; nam_apap137-2_42 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1928-1944; nam_apap137-2_43 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1956-1957; nam_apap137-2_44 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1959-1960; nam_apap137-2_45 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1961-1963; nam_apap137-2_46 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1964-1966; nam_apap137-2_47 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1967-1969; nam_apap137-2_48 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1970-1971; nam_apap137-2_49 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1972-1973; nam_apap137-2_50 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1974-1975; nam_apap137-2_51 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1976-1977; nam_apap137-2_52 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1980-1982; nam_apap137-2_53 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1983-1984; nam_apap137-2_54 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1985; nam_apap137-2_55 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors, Treasury Reports, 1986-1987; nam_apap137-2_56 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors, Trial Balance, 1980; nam_apap137-2_57 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Board of Trustees, Correspondence, 1980-1988; nam_apap137-2_58 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1933-1964; nam_apap137-2_59 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1978-1980; nam_apap137-2_60 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1983-1985; nam_apap137-2_61 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1986-1987; nam_apap137-2_62 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1988-1989; nam_apap137-2_63 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Board of Trustees, Meeting Minutes, 1990-1995; nam_apap137-2_64 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Board of Trustees, Officer Lists and Organizational Structure, 1983-1989; nam_apap137-2_65 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Board of Trustees, Responsibilities, Undated; nam_apap137-2_66 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Board of Trustees, Retirement Fund, 1976-1990; nam_apap137-2_67 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Cafeteria Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1944-1951; nam_apap137-2_68 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cafeteria Committee, Reports, 1944-1951; nam_apap137-2_69 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Centennial Committee Guide for Commemoration, 1955; nam_apap137-2_70 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Centennial Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1988; nam_apap137-2_71 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Committee and Job Descriptions, Undated; nam_apap137-2_72 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Department Report, 1963; nam_apap137-2_73 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Executive Board, Meeting Minutes, 1985; nam_apap137-2_74 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1933-1936; nam_apap137-2_75 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1937-1941; nam_apap137-2_76 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1954-1955; nam_apap137-2_77 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1956-1957; nam_apap137-2_78 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1958-1959; nam_apap137-2_79 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1969-1970; 1973-1975; nam_apap137-2_80 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1979-1984; nam_apap137-2_81 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1985-1989; nam_apap137-2_82 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Executive Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1991; nam_apap137-2_83 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Executive and Finance Committee, Meeting Minutes, Advisors and Building Committee Meeting Minutes, 1964; nam_apap137-2_84 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Finance Committee, Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1983-1994; nam_apap137-2_85 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Finance Committee, Notes, 1930-1933; nam_apap137-2_86 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Finance Manuals and Treasury Responsibilities, Undated; nam_apap137-2_87 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Health Department Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1959; nam_apap137-2_88 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - House Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1934-1945; nam_apap137-2_89 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Membership Committee, Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1984-1987; nam_apap137-2_90 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - National YWCA, Meeting Minutes Concerning Tax Legislation, 1979; nam_apap137-2_91 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - National YWCA Board, Treasurer's Report, 1980-1981; nam_apap137-2_92 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Nominating Committee, Meeting Minutes and Agendas, 1984-1988; nam_apap137-2_93 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Race Relations Committee, 1983-1985; nam_apap137-2_94 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Residence Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1959-1962; nam_apap137-2_95 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Resource Development Committee, Meeting Minutes and Correspondence, 1979; nam_apap137-2_96 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Staff and Board of Directors Workshop, 1986; nam_apap137-2_97 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Staff Meeting, Minutes and Agendas, 1987-1988; nam_apap137-2_98 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Supervisory Group Report, 1990; nam_apap137-2_99 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Thursday Afternoon Club, Federated Business and Professional Club Papers (from scrapbook), 1939-1940; nam_apap137-2_100 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Tribute Committee Report, 1985; nam_apap137-2_101 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Various Committee Meeting Minutes, 1962-1974; nam_apap137-2_102 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - World Fellowship Committee, Meeting Minutes, 1959-1963; nam_apap137-2_103 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - World Fellowship Committee, Meeting Minutes, Undated; nam_apap137-2_104 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Youth Committee Meeting, 1978; nam_apap137-2_105 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - YWCA Organizational Cart, 1987; nam_apap137-2_106 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Board of Directors, Treasurer's Report, 1981; nam_apap137-2_107 (Box 1A, Folder 19)
  - Tribute Committee Meeting, 1985; nam_apap137-2_108 (Box 1A, Folder 20)
- Public Relations, Programs, and Events, 1911-1995; nam_apap137-3; 1.22 cubic ft.
  This series documents the YWCA programs, newsletters and special events from 1911 to 1995. Materials include class offerings, Black History Month essay contest programs and essays, annual Tribute to Women award ceremony materials, brochures, and fliers.
  - Albany YWCA Health Parade Bulletins, 1940; nam_apap137-3_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Women; 1607 to Present, 6 volumes, 1978; nam_apap137-3_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Association Hymnal, 1926; nam_apap137-3_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Black History Month Essay Contest, 1985-1991; nam_apap137-3_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Brochures, Fliers, and Programs, 1911-1939; nam_apap137-3_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Brochures, Fliers, and Programs, 1940-1949; nam_apap137-3_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Brochures, Fliers, and Programs, 1959-1984; nam_apap137-3_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Brochures, Fliers, and Programs, Undated; nam_apap137-3_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brochures of Workshops and Classes, 1977-1982; Undated; nam_apap137-3_9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Brochures of Workshops and Classes, 1983-1987; nam_apap137-3_10 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brochures of Workshops and Classes, 1988-1989; nam_apap137-3_11 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brochures of Workshops and Classes, 1990-1992; nam_apap137-3_12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brochures of Workshops and Classes, 1993-1995; nam_apap137-3_13 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Federated Business Girls Club, Programs and Newsletters, 1939; nam_apap137-3_14 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fliers (non-Albany related), 1941-1949; 1958; nam_apap137-3_15 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Guest Book, 1979; nam_apap137-3_16 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Guest Book, Undated; nam_apap137-3_17 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - In Behalf of Working Women, YWCA Record, Undated; nam_apap137-3_18 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Industrial Awakening and the YWCA, 1920; nam_apap137-3_19 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Introducing the YWCA to New Members, 1937; nam_apap137-3_20 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Life Process Center for Women, Undated; nam_apap137-3_21 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Music, Let's Have More of It, 1960; nam_apap137-3_22 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Newsletters, 1940; nam_apap137-3_23 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Our Faith and Ourselves Today, 1955; nam_apap137-3_24 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Public Affairs in the YWCA, 1957; nam_apap137-3_25 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Public Affairs Newsletters and Correspondence, 1979; nam_apap137-3_26 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Skits and Songs, Undated; nam_apap137-3_27 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Thursday Afternoon Club, Programs, ca. 1940s; nam_apap137-3_28 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Tribute to Women, Biographies, Undated; nam_apap137-3_29 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony Programs, 1979-1985; nam_apap137-3_30 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony Programs, 1986-1987; nam_apap137-3_31 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony Programs, 1988-1990; nam_apap137-3_32 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony Programs, 1991-1994; nam_apap137-3_33 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Citation and Resolution of 100th Anniversary, 1988; nam_apap137-3_34 (Box 1A, Folder 21)
  - Black History Month Certificate and Proclamation, 1990; nam_apap137-3_35 (Box 1A, Folder 22)
  - Display Descriptions, Undated; nam_apap137-3_36 (Box 1A, Folder 23)
  - Member Certificate, 1909; nam_apap137-3_37 (Box 1A, Folder 24)
  - Newsletter, 1940; nam_apap137-3_38 (Box 1A, Folder 25)
  - Proclamation, YWCA of Albany Month, 1988; nam_apap137-3_39 (Box 1A, Folder 26)
  - Winter 1998 Program, Rough Draft, 1988; nam_apap137-3_40 (Box 1A, Folder 27)
  - African American History Month Proclamation, 1994; nam_apap137-3_41 (Oversized 2, Folder 6)
  - The Albany Review, 1989; nam_apap137-3_42 (Oversized 2, Folder 7)
  - Citation, 1988; nam_apap137-3_43 (Oversized 2, Folder 8)
  - Newspapers, 1974; 1989; nam_apap137-3_44 (Oversized 2, Folder 9)
  - Poster American Women, 1983; nam_apap137-3_45 (Oversized 2, Folder 10)
  - Poster Women Veterans, Undated; nam_apap137-3_46 (Oversized 2, Folder 11)
  - Posters Women's History Week, Undated; nam_apap137-3_47 (Oversized 2, Folder 12-16)
- News Clippings and Scrapbook Material, 1905-1995; nam_apap137-4; 0.99 cubic ft.
  This series consists of photocopies of news clippings and scrapbook materials pertaining to the Albany YWCA and/or collected by the Albany YWCA from 1905 to 1995. Whenever possible, the original order of the scrapbooks is maintained, which does not always correspond with chronological order. Loose news clippings and loose scrapbook pages are organized by date. Original items in scrapbooks, such as programs, photographs, postcards, and letters are filed separately within the series.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - News Clippings, 1905-1925; nam_apap137-4_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - News Clippings, 1930-1939; nam_apap137-4_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - News Clippings, 1940-1949; nam_apap137-4_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - News Clippings, 1950-1959; nam_apap137-4_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - News Clippings, 1960-1974; nam_apap137-4_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - News Clippings, 1982-1989; nam_apap137-4_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings, 1991-1995; nam_apap137-4_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - News Clippings, Poster Photocopy, 1994; nam_apap137-4_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - News Clippings, ca. 1950s; nam_apap137-4_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - News Clippings, 1989-1990; nam_apap137-4_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - News Clippings, ca. 1990s; nam_apap137-4_11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - News Clippings, Undated; nam_apap137-4_12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - News Clippings, Thursday Afternoon Club, Undated; nam_apap137-4_13 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook, Originals, ca. 1910s-1940s; nam_apap137-4_14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook, Photocopies, ca. 1910s-1940s; nam_apap137-4_15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook, Originals, ca. 1930s; nam_apap137-4_16 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook, Originals, ca. 1930s; nam_apap137-4_17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook, Photo Album, ca. 1930s; nam_apap137-4_18 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Scrapbook, Photo Album, ca. 1930s; nam_apap137-4_19 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Scrapbook, Loose Pages and News Clippings, ca. 1930s-1960s; nam_apap137-4_20 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook, Loose Pages and News Clippings, ca. 1957-1959; Undated; nam_apap137-4_21 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1932-1936; nam_apap137-4_22 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1937-1938; nam_apap137-4_23 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1938-1939; nam_apap137-4_24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1939; nam_apap137-4_25 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1939; nam_apap137-4_26 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1939-1940; nam_apap137-4_27 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, Originals, 1939-1949; nam_apap137-4_28 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, Photocopies, 1939-1949; nam_apap137-4_29 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, Originals, Publicity Reports, 1940-1941; nam_apap137-4_30 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, Publicity Reports, Photocopies, 1940-1941; nam_apap137-4_31 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1940; nam_apap137-4_32 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook, Originals, ca. 1940s; nam_apap137-4_33 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook, Thursday Afternoon Club, 1940-1941; nam_apap137-4_34 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, Business and Professional Club, 1941-1942; nam_apap137-4_35 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, Girls Reserve, 1941-1945; nam_apap137-4_36 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1950-1954; nam_apap137-4_37 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, Outing Club, Originals, 1952-1953; nam_apap137-4_38 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, Outing Club, Photocopies, 1952-1953; nam_apap137-4_39 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1954; nam_apap137-4_40 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1956-1958; nam_apap137-4_41 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1963; nam_apap137-4_42 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1963; nam_apap137-4_43 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1964; nam_apap137-4_44 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbook, 1965; nam_apap137-4_45 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbook, 1965-1967; nam_apap137-4_46 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Scrapbook, 1981-1983; nam_apap137-4_47 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Scrapbook, 1983-1985; nam_apap137-4_48 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbook, 1986-1989; nam_apap137-4_49 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Scrapbook, 1989-1990; nam_apap137-4_50 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Scrapbook, 1990-1993; nam_apap137-4_51 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Photographs, 1911-1995; nam_apap137-5; 2.64 cubic ft.
  This series holds photographs documenting YWCA activities and programs covering 1936 to 1995, particularly the annual Tribute to Women. It consists of color and black and white prints, slides, and negatives. There is tape damage on some prints. The majority of the pictures are from the 1980s and 1990s. One photograph is available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database.
  One photograph is available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database
  - Aerobics, Black and White, 1983-1986; nam_apap137-5_1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aerobics, Black and White, 1987-1989; nam_apap137-5_2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Aerobics, Black and White, 1990-1995; Undated; nam_apap137-5_3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Aerobics, Children, 1987; 1989-1990; Undated; nam_apap137-5_4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aerobics, Color, 1987-1990; Undated; nam_apap137-5_5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Dinners, 1983; 1985; nam_apap137-5_6 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Black History Month Essay Contest, 1980; 1982-1984; nam_apap137-5_7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Black History Month Essay Contest, 1988; 1990; 1992-1993; nam_apap137-5_8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Black History Month Essay Contest, Undated; nam_apap137-5_9 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Children, 1958-1960; 1962; 1966; nam_apap137-5_10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Children, 1983-1986; nam_apap137-5_11 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Children, 1987-1989; nam_apap137-5_12 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Children, 1990-1994; nam_apap137-5_13 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Children, Undated; nam_apap137-5_14 (Box 2, Folder 4-7)
  - Children, Christmas Parties, 1988; 1991; Undated; nam_apap137-5_15 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Drop-In Child Center, Undated; nam_apap137-5_16 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Empire State Plaza, Demonstrations, 1984; nam_apap137-5_17 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Empire State Plaza, Demonstrations, 1985; nam_apap137-5_18 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Empire State Black Arts and Cultural Festival, 1985; nam_apap137-5_19 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fire Trucks Program, 1990; 1992; 1994; Undated; nam_apap137-5_20 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Gallery Exhibits, 1978-1979; Undated; nam_apap137-5_21 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Garage Sale, 1984-1985; 1987-1989; nam_apap137-5_22 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Garage Sale, 1990; 1992; nam_apap137-5_23 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Golden Rule Awards, 1990; nam_apap137-5_24 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Great Escape Trip, 1992; nam_apap137-5_25 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Group Activities, 1970-1979; nam_apap137-5_26 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Group Activities, 1980-1983; 1985-1989; nam_apap137-5_27 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Group Activities, 1990; Undated; nam_apap137-5_28 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Halloween Parties, 1987-1989; Undated; nam_apap137-5_29 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Indoor Sports, 1936; 1944; 1980; Undated; nam_apap137-5_30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Martial Arts, 1960; 1987; 1989; 1993; Undated; nam_apap137-5_31 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mayor's Office Proclamation, 1988; nam_apap137-5_32 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Mom and Tot Group, 1984-1986; nam_apap137-5_33 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Negatives, 35mm, 1975; 1986; Undated; nam_apap137-5_34 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Negatives, 35mm, Various Activities, Undated; nam_apap137-5_35 (Box 4, Folder 7-10)
  - Negatives, Film Size 110 and 126, Various Activities, Undated; nam_apap137-5_36 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - People, Identified, 1948; 1950; 1952; 1957-1969; nam_apap137-5_37 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - People, Identified, 1983-1988; 1990; 1992-1993; nam_apap137-5_38 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - People, Identified, Undated; nam_apap137-5_39 (Box 5, Folder 4-5)
  - People, Unidentified, 1980-1981; 1984-1986; nam_apap137-5_40 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - People, Unidentified, 1987-1989; nam_apap137-5_41 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - People, Unidentified, 1990-1993; nam_apap137-5_42 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - People, Unidentified, Undated; nam_apap137-5_43 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - People, Unidentified, Undated; nam_apap137-5_44 (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
  - Slides, Aerobics, Children, Christmas, Essay Contest, Swimming, Undated; nam_apap137-5_45 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Summer Activities, 1961; 1971; nam_apap137-5_46 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Summer Fun Day Camp, 1987; 1990; 1992; nam_apap137-5_47 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Swimming, 1944; 1959; 1983; 1985-1989; 1991-1992; nam_apap137-5_48 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Swimming, Undated; nam_apap137-5_49 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1980; 1982; nam_apap137-5_50 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Tribute to Women, Ceremony and Honorees, 1983-1984; nam_apap137-5_51 (Box 7, Folder 2)